Dorchester, Boston, Mass. Second Church records, 1770-1991.
Congregational Library Archives
- Finances, 1806 1989; 1806-1989; 129 Items
  - Trust fund, 1946 1981; 1946-1981; 8 Items
    - Reports on Trust Funds, 1971 1977; 1971-1977 (Box 29, Folder 24)
    - Stocks and Trust Funds, 1978 (Box 29, Folder 25)
    - Reports on Trust Funds, 1978 1981; 1978-1981 (Box 29, Folder 26)
  - Quarterly returns, 1962 1971; 1962-1971; 3 Items
    This sub-series contains quarterly returns for the Second Church.
    - Quarterly Returns, 1962 1964; 1962-1964 (Box 28, Folder 64)
    - Quarterly Returns, 1965 1968; 1965-1968 (Box 28, Folder 65)
    - Quarterly Returns, 1969 1971; 1969-1971 (Box 28, Folder 66)
  - Income, 1963 1988; 1963-1988; 5 Items
    This sub-series contains income records.
    - Income, 1963 1968; 1963-1968 (Box 5, Volume 1)
    - Income, 1969 1973; 1969-1973 (Box 5, Volume 2)
    - Income, 1974 1978; 1974-1978 (Box 5, Volume 3)
    - Income, 1979 1984; 1979-1984 (Box 5, Volume 4)
    - Income, 1984-05 1988; May 1984 - 1988 (Box 6, Volume 2)
  - Budgets, 1968 1986; 1968-1986; 3 Items
    This sub-series contains proposed budgets for Second Church.
    - Proposed Budgets, 1968 1973; 1968-1973 (Box 29, Folder 15)
    - Proposed Budgets, 1980 1986; 1980-1986 (Box 29, Folder 16)
    - Proposed Budgets, 1983 (Box 29, Folder 17)
- Auxiliary organizations, 1813 1984; 1813-1984; 94 Items
  This series contains information for multiple auxiliary organizations affiliated with Second Church and include the Dorchester Female Benevolent Society, Sunday School, Sabbath School, Ladies Missionary Association, Home Missionary Society, Ladies Home Missionary Society, Foreign Missionary Society, Maternal Association, Dorchester Women's Missionary Society, Social Bible Class, Young People's Society, Codman Guild, Dorcas Society, Ladies Foreign Missionary Society, Junior Christian Endeavor Society, Young Ladies Missionary Society, Music Department, Women's Home Mission Auxiliary, Baraca Class, Chinese Sunday School, Men's Club, Codman Class, Teacher's Club, Philathea Class, Dorchester Gentlemen's Driving Club, Monday Missionary Society, Boys' Brass Band, Second Church Auxiliary, Women's Association, Bumpus Memorial Class, Codman Glee Club, Phi Sigma Phi, Couples Club, Adult Fellowship, Dorchester Women's Club, Religious Education Committee, Missionary Committee, NEPCO Senior Citizens, Bible Club of Boston and the Mutual Admiration Society.
  - Dorchester Female Benevolent Society, 1813 1855; 1813-1855; 2 Items
    This sub-series contains treasurer information and records for the Dorchester Female Benevolent Society.
    - Dorchester Female Benevolent Society Treasurer's records, 1813 1852; 1813-1852 (Box 22, Volume 10)
    - Dorchester Female Benevolent Society records, 1840 1855; 1840-1855 (Box 22, Volume 11)
  - Sunday School, 1818 1980; 1818-1980; 11 Items
    This sub-series contains records for the Sunday School, including reports, timelines, class records, expenses, benevolences and anniversaries.
    - Sunday School records, May 31, 1818 (Box 20, Volume 13)
    - Sunday School reports, 1850 1862; 1850-1862 (Box 20, Volume 14)
    - Sunday School timelines, 1852 1875; 1852-1875 (Box 31, Folder 11)
    - 70th Anniversary of the Congregational Sunday School, June 13, 1886 (Box 31, Folder 30)
    - Sunday School expenses and benevolences, 1892 1903; 1892-1903 (Box 20, Volume 16)
    - Sunday School minutes, 1892 1921; 1892-1921 (Box 20, Volume 15)
    - Sunday School records, 1894 1895; 1894-1895 (Box 20, Volume 17)
    - Sunday School Treasurer's reports, 1904 (Box 20, Volume 18)
    - Sunday School Class Records, 1938 1941; 1938-1941 (Box 31, Folder 12)
    - Sunday School Records, 1949 1963; 1949-1963 (Box 31, Folder 13)
    - Sunday School Rally Days, 1980 (Box 25, Folder 50)
  - Sabbath School, 1820 1933; 1820-1878, 1914-1933; 2 Items
    This sub-series contains records for the Sabbath School and also includes secretary records.
    - Sabbath School Society records, 1820-1878 (Box 33, Volume 4)
    - Sabbath School Secretary's records, 1914 1933; 1914-1933 (Box 20, Volume 21)
  - Ladies Missionary Association, 1826 1871; 1826-1871; 1 Item
    This sub-series contains records of the Ladies Missionary Association.
    - Ladies Missionary Association records, 1826 1871; 1826-1871 (Box 20, Volume 8)
  - Home Missionary Society, 1828 1832; 1828-1832; 1 Item
    This sub-series contains meeting minutes of the Home Missionary Society.
    - Home Missionary Society meeting minutes, 1828 1832; 1828-1832 (Box 22, Volume 21)
  - Ladies Home Missionary Society, 1828 1899; 1828-1899; 2 Items
    This sub-series contains records and secretary notes from the Ladies Home Missionary Society.
    - Ladies Home Missionary Society records, 1828 1852; 1828-1852 (Box 22, Volume 22)
    - Ladies Home Missionary Society secretary notes, 1853 1899; 1853-1899 (Box 22, Volume 23)
  - Foreign Missionary Society, 1828 1935; 1828-1867, 1930-1935; 4 Items
    This sub-series contains meeting minutes, by-laws, treasurer's records and a list of deceased members of the Foreign Missionary Society.
    - Foreign Missionary Society Treasurer's records, 1828 1865; 1828-1865 (Box 22, Volume 17)
    - Foreign Missions Society List of Deceased Members, 1853 1867; 1853-1867 (Box 25, Folder 49)
    - Foreign Missionary Society Meeting Minutes, 1930 1935; 1930-1935 (Box 22, Volume 18)
    - Excerpt of By-Laws of Foreign Missionary Society, undated (Box 31, Folder 38)
  - Maternal Association, 1851 1881; 1851-1881; 1 Item
    This sub-series contains records of the Maternal Association.
    - Maternal Association records, 1851 1881; 1851-1881 (Box 20, Volume 12)
  - Dorchester Women's Missionary Society, 1870 1895; 1870-1895; 1 Item
    This sub-series contains records of the Dorchester Women's Missionary Society.
    - Dorchester Women's Missionary Society records, 1870 1895; 1870-1895 (Box 20, Volume 11)
  - Social Bible Class, 1885; 1 Item
    This sub-series contains records of the Social Bible Class.
    - Social Bible Class records, 1885, undated (Box 31, Folder 29)
  - Young People's Society, 1886 1890; 1886-1890; 1 Item
    This sub-series contains records of the Young People's Society.
    - Young People's Society records, 1886 1890; 1886-1890 (Box 20, Volume 10)
  - Codman Guild, 1893 1949; 1893-1949; 4 Items
    This sub-series contains records of the Codman Guild and includes meeting minutes, constitution, membership and secretary notes.
    - Codman Guild Meeting Minutes, 1893 1903; 1893-1903 (Box 22, Volume 12)
    - Codman Guild Constitution and Membership, 1896 1911; 1896-1911 (Box 22, Volume 13)
    - Codman Guild records, 1903 1912; 1903-1912 (Box 22, Volume 14)
    - Codman Guild Secretary's notes, 1912 1921; 1912-1921 (Box 22, Volume 15)
  - Dorcas Society, 1894 1915; 1894-1915; 2 Items
    This sub-series contains records of the Dorcas Society.
    - Dorcas Society records, 1894 1904; 1894-1904 (Box 22, Volume 19)
    - Dorcas Society records, 1905 1915; 1905-1915 (Box 22, Volume 20)
  - Ladies Foreign Missionary Society, 1895 1909; 1895-1909; 2 Items
    This sub-series contains records of the Ladies Foreign Missionary Society.
    - Ladies Foreign Missionary Society records, 1895 1905; 1895-1905 (Box 22, Volume 4)
    - Ladies Foreign Missionary Society records, 1905 1909; 1905-1909 (Box 22, Volume 5)
  - Junior Christian Endeavor Society, 1897 1911; 1897-1911; 5 Items
    This sub-series contains records and vouchers for the Junior Christian Endeavor Society.
    - Junior Christian Endeavor Society records, 1897 1899; 1897-1899 (Box 31, Folder 5)
    - Junior Christian Endeavor Society records, 1900 1904; 1900-1904 (Box 31, Folder 6)
    - Vouchers for Junior Christian Endeavor Society, 1901 (Box 31, Folder 7)
    - Vouchers for Junior Christian Endeavor Society, 1902 1908; 1902-1908 (Box 31, Folder 8)
    - Junior Christian Endeavor Society records, 1910 1911; 1910-1911 (Box 20, Volume 9)
  - Young Ladies Missionary Society, 1898 1916; 1898-1916; 3 Items
    This sub-series contains records for the Young Ladies Missionary Society.
    - Young Ladies Missionary Society records, 1898 1940; 1898-1904 (Box 22, Volume 1)
    - Young Ladies Missionary Society records, 1904 1910; 1904-1910 (Box 22, Volume 2)
    - Young Ladies Missionary Society records, 1910 1916; 1910-1916 (Box 22, Volume 3)
  - Music Department, 1898 1923; 1898-1923; 1 Item
    This sub-series contains the account book for the Music Department.
    - Music Department Account Book, 1898 1923; 1898-1923 (Box 33, Volume 2)
  - Women's Home Mission Auxiliary, 1899 1920; 1899-1920; 3 Items
    This sub-series contains records of the Women's Home Mission Auxiliary.
    - Women's Home Missions Auxiliary records, 1899 1909; 1899-1909 (Box 20, Volume 5)
    - Women's Home Missions Auxiliary records, 1910 1911; 1910-1911 (Box 31, Folder 31)
    - Women's Home Missions Auxiliary records, 1910 1920; 1910-1920 (Box 20, Volume 6)
  - Baraca Class, 1905 1929; 1905-1929; 5 Items
    This sub-series contains records, files and a service of the Baraca Class.
    - Baraca Class records, 1905 1926; 1905-1926 (Box 21, Volume 2)
    - Baraca Class Files, 1905 1929; 1905-1929 (Box 31, Folder 14)
    - Baraca-Philatheas Service, 1916-05-13 1916-05-14; May 13 - 14, 1916 (Box 31, Folder 15)
    - Baraca Class records, 1921 1926; 1921-1926 (Box 21, Volume 3)
    - Baraca Class records, 1928 1929; 1928-1929 (Box 21, Volume 4)
  - Chinese Sunday School, 1909 1935; 1909, 1934-1935; 2 Items
    This sub-series contains records and a mandarin version of the Book of Acts from the Chinese Sunday School.
    - Chinese Sunday School's Copy of The Book of Acts in Mandarin, 1909 (Box 31, Folder 9)
    - Chinese Sunday School Records, 1934 1935; 1934-1935 (Box 31, Folder 10)
  - Men's Club, 1909 1920; 1909-1920; 1 Item
    This sub-series contains records of the Men's Club.
    - Men's Club records, 1909 1920; 1909-1920 (Box 21, Volume 13)
  - Codman Class, 1909 1951; 1909-1951; 5 Items
    This sub-series contains records, by-laws, membership, names, addresses and excerpts of the Codman Class.
    - Codman Class By-Laws and Membership, 1909 1951; 1909-1951 (Box 22, Volume 16)
    - Codman Class Excerpt, November 19, 1925 (Box 31, Folder 1)
    - Codman Class Names and Addresses, 1932 1949; 1932-1949 (Box 31, Folder 2)
    - Codman Class Records, 1938 1944; 1938-1944 (Box 31, Folder 3)
    - Codman Class Records, 1944 1949; 1944-1949 (Box 31, Folder 4)
  - Teacher's Club, 1911 1935; 1911-1935; 1 Item
    This sub-series contains records of the Teacher's Club.
    - Teacher's Club records, 1911 1935; 1911-1935 (Box 21, Volume 14)
  - Philathea Class, 1912 1916; 1912-1916; 1 Item
    This sub-series contains records of the Philathea Class.
    - Philathea Class records, 1912 1916; 1912-1916 (Box 21, Volume 1)
  - Dorchester Gentlemen's Driving Club, 1913 1915; 1913-1915; 2 Items
    This sub-series contains records of the Dorchester Gentlemen's Driving Club.
    - Dorchester Gentlemen's Driving Club records, 1913 (Box 31, Folder 18)
    - Dorchester Gentlemen's Driving Club records, 1913 1915; 1913-1915 (Box 31, Folder 19)
  - Monday Missionary Society, 1916 1961; 1916-1961; 6 Items
    This sub-series contains records, memberships, meeting minutes and a guestbook of the Monday Missionary Society.
    - Monday Missionary Society records, 1916 1928; 1916-1928 (Box 22, Volume 6)
    - Monday Missionary Society records, 1921 1928; 1921-1928 (Box 22, Volume 7)
    - Monday Missionary Society memberships, 1929 1934; 1929, 1934 (Box 31, Folder 16)
    - Monday Missionary Society guestbook, 1929 1961; 1929-1961 (Box 22, Volume 8)
    - Monday Missionary Society meeting minutes, 1931-02-02 1933-06-05; February 2, 1931 - June 5, 1933 (Box 31, Folder 17)
    - Monday Missionary Society records, 1937 1947; 1935-1947 (Box 22, Volume 9)
  - Boys' Brass Band, 1917 1920; 1917-1920; 1 Item
    This sub-series contains records of the Boys' Brass Band.
    - Boys' Brass Band records, 1917 1920; 1917-1920 (Box 31, Folder 32)
  - Second Church Auxiliary, 1918-01 1922-05; January 1918 - May 1922; 1 Item
    This sub-series contains records of the Second Church Auxiliary.
    - Records of Second Church Auxiliary, 1918-01-01 1922-05; January 1918 - May 1922 (Box 33, Volume 3)
  - Women's Association, 1922 1984; 1922-1984; 3 Items
    This sub-series contains records, minutes and treasurer's reports of the Women's Association.
    - Women's Association records, 1922 1930; 1922-1930 (Box 20, Volume 2)
    - Women's Association Treasurer's reports, 1957 1976; 1957-1976 (Box 20, Volume 3)
    - Women's Association minutes, 1975 1984; 1975-1984 (Box 20, Volume 4)
  - Bumpus Memorial Class, 1925 1932; 1925-1932; 1 Item
    This sub-series contains records of the Bumpus Memorial Class.
    - Bumpus Memorial Class records, 1925 1932; 1925-1932 (Box 20, Volume 7)
  - Codman Glee Club, 1926-02-22 1926-02-23; February 22-23, 1927; 1 Item
    This sub-series contains a pamphlet of the Six Annual Minstrel Show by the Codman Glee Club.
    - Six Annual Minstrel Show Pamphlet, 1927-02-22 1927-02-23; February 22-23, 1927 (Box 31, Folder 33)
  - Phi Sigma Phi, 1928 1976; 1928-1976; 7 Items
    This sub-series contains records from Phi Sigma Phi.
    - Phi Sigma Phi records, 1928 1967; 1928-1967 (Box 24, Folder 13)
    - Phi Sigma Phi records, 1936 1938; 1936-1938 (Box 21, Volume 9)
    - Phi Sigma Phi records, 1939 1946; 1939-1946 (Box 21, Volume 10)
    - Phi Sigma Phi records, 1939 1949; 1939-1949 (Box 31, Folder 40)
    - Phi Sigma Phi records, 1946 1976; 1946-1976 (Box 21, Volume 11)
    - Phi Sigma Phi records, 1946-09-11 1962; September 11, 1946 - 1962 (Box 10, Volume 1)
    - Phi Sigma Phi records, 1959-09-12 1969-05-13; September 12, 1959 - May 13, 1969 (Box 10, Volume 2)
  - Couples Club, 1943 1953; 1943-1953; 3 Items
    This sub-series contains records, meeting minutes and a guestbook for the Couples Club.
    - Couples Club records, 1943 1953; 1943-1953 (Box 31, Folder 20)
    - Couples Club meeting minutes, 1948 1953; 1948-1953 (Box 31, Folder 21)
    - Couples Club guestbook, October 29, 1949 (Box 31, Folder 22)
  - Adult Fellowship, 1953 1957; 1953-1957; 1 Item
    This sub-series contains records of the Adult Fellowship.
    - Adult Fellowship records, 1953 1957; 1953-1957 (Box 31, Folder 34)
  - Dorchester Women's Club, 1963-02-01 1963-02-28; February 1963; 1 Item
    This sub-series contains records of the Dorchester Women's Club.
    - Dorchester Women's Club records, 1963-02-01 1963-02-28; February 1963 (Box 31, Folder 35)
  - Religious Education Committee, 1979 1981; 1979-1981; 1 Item
    This sub-series contains meeting minutes of the Religious Education Committee.
    - Religious Education Committee meeting minutes, 1979 1981; 1979-1981 (Box 31, Folder 36)
  - Missionary Committee, 1981; 1 Item
    This sub-series contains meeting minutes of the Missionary Committee.
    - Missionary Committee meeting minutes, 1981 (Box 31, Folder 37)
  - NEPCO Senior Citizens, 1981 1982; 1981-1982; 1 Item
    This sub-series contains records of the NEPCO Senior Citizens.
    - NEPCO Senior Citizens records, 1981 1982; 1981-1982 (Box 25, Folder 51)
  - Bible Club of Boston, undated; 1 Item
    This sub-series contains members of the Bible Club of Boston.
    - Members of Bible Club of Boston, undated (Box 32, Folder 1)
  - Mutual Admiration Society, undated; 1 Item
    This sub-series contains sheet music for the Mutual Admiration Society.
    - Mutual Admiration Society sheet music, undated (Box 25, Folder 52)
- Pastoral records, 1830 1982; 1830-1982; 64 Items
  This series contains the records of Second Church's pastors and include Rev. Dr. John Codman, Rev. James H. Means, Rev. Edward N. Packard, Rev. Arthur Little, Rev. Jason Noble Pierce, Rev. Vaughn Dabney, Rev. Andrew Richards, Rev. Frank T. Jensen and Rev. Thomas G. Jones. Also included are records about other churches pastors, reports and letters.
  - Rev. Dr. John Codman, 1830 1839; 1830-1839; 1 Item
    This sub-series contains information on Dr. Codman's Parish Party.
    - Dr. Codman's Parish Party, 1830 1839; 1830-1839 (Box 25, Folder 1)
  - Rev. James H. Means, 1848 1873; 1848-1873; 1 Item
    This sub-series contains records of Reverend James H. Means.
    - Reverend James H. Means Records, 1848 1873; 1848-1873 (Box 31, Folder 39)
  - Records about other church pastors, 1868 1982; 1868, 1952, 1967, 1982; 7 Items
    This sub-series contains various information on pastors from other churches. Included are Reverend William H. H. Murray, Reverend Craig H. Richards, Reverend Arthur S. Blowen, Reverend Philip J. Bauman, Reverend James R. Haun and Reverend George E. Weaver.
    - Invitation to Reverend William H. H. Murray's Installation, November 5, 1868 (Box 21, Folder 1)
    - Reverend Craig H. Richards Congratulatory Letter, 1952 (Box 30, Folder 67)
    - Special Report on Reverend Arthur S. Blowen, March 9, 1967 (Box 25, Folder 4)
    - Rescind Reverend Arthur S. Blowen, February 1, 1967 (Box 30, Folder 58)
    - Ordination of Reverend Philip J. Bauman, January 10, 1982 (Box 30, Folder 62)
    - Reverend James R. Haun Evaluations and Ordination, 1982 (Box 30, Folder 63)
    - Remarks at the funeral of Reverend George E. Weaver, undated (Box 30, Folder 64)
  - Rev. Edward N. Packard, April 8, 1879; 1 Item
    This sub-series contains the installation information for Reverend Edward N. Packard.
    - Installation of Reverend Edward N. Packard, April 8, 1879 (Box 30, Folder 53)
  - Rev. Arthur Little, 1888 1916; 1888-1916; 6 Items
    This sub-series contains letters, records, a picture, death and memorial of Reverend Arthur Little.
    - Letters Welcoming Reverend Arthur Little to Boston, 1888 (Box 30, Folder 41)
    - Reverend Arthur Little's Pastorship, 1889-1913 (Box 30, Folder 42)
    - Letter from Charles Pope to Reverend Arthur Little, December 24, 1907 (Box 30, Folder 43)
    - Letter to Reverend Arthur Little, January 11, 1908 (Box 30, Folder 44)
    - Death and Memorial of Reverend Arthur Little, 1915 1916; 1915-1916 (Box 30, Folder 45)
    - Picture of Reverend Arthur Little, undated (Box 30, Folder 46)
  - Reports and letters, 1896 1987; 1896-1987; 12 Items
    This sub-series contains reports and letters related to pastors at Second Church. This includes deaconess reports, deacon letter and tributes, Pastor's annual reports, nominating committee reports and pastoral correspondences.
    - Deaconess reports, 1896 1922; 1896-1922 (Box 21, Volume 12)
    - Records of Joint Committee on Pastor, 1912 1914; 1912-1914 (Box 28, Folder 27)
    - Deacon Correspondences, 1918 1920; 1918-1920 (Box 30, Folder 66)
    - Pastor and Religious Educational Reports, January 24, 1935 (Box 28, Folder 16)
    - Pastor's Annual Reports, 1944 1965; 1944-1965 (Box 28, Folder 15)
    - Tribute to Deacon Aberdeen W. Child, January 23, 1947 (Box 30, Folder 56)
    - Letter from Reverend Ernest Patton to Janet Robinson about Hurricanes, October 29, 1954 (Box 30, Folder 57)
    - Assistant Pastor Letter, November 12, 1954 (Box 30, Folder 68)
    - Nomination Committee reports, 1972 1983; 1972-1983 (Box 28, Folder 33)
    - Deacon's Fund, 1973 1980; 1973-1981 (Box 28, Folder 34)
    - Seasonal Pastoral Letters, 1979 1986; 1979-1986 (Box 30, Folder 70)
    - Pastoral Correspondences, 1980 1987; 1980-1987 (Box 30, Folder 72)
  - Rev. Jason Noble Pierce, 1914 1947; 1914-1947; 8 Items
    This sub-series contains records, letters, writings, a photo and the call from the ecclesiastical council of Jason Noble Pierce.
    - Candidate Reverend Jason Noble Pierce, 1914 (Box 30, Folder 47)
    - Reverend Jason Noble Pierce records, 1916 1947; 1916-1947 (Box 25, Folder 2)
    - Pulpit Committee, 1918 (Box 30, Folder 65)
    - War Bond Drive and Reverend Jason Noble Pierce, 1918 (Box 30, Folder 48)
    - Reverend Jason Noble Pierce's WWI Field Correspondences, 1918-07 1919-02; July 1918 - February 1919 (Box 30, Folder 49)
    - Reverend Jason Noble Pierce's Writing, 1919, undated (Box 30, Folder 50)
    - Photo of Mary and Jason Noble Pierce, May 4, 1928 (Box 30, Folder 51)
    - Call for Ecclesiastical Council regarding Reverend Jason Noble Pierce, undated (Box 30, Folder 52)
  - Rev. Vaughn Dabney, 1924 1929; 1924-1929; 2 Items
    This sub-series contains a report and a letter from Vaughn Dabney.
    - Reverend Vaughn Dabney Letter, December 2, 1924 (Box 30, Folder 54)
    - Reverend Vaughn Dabney Report, September 12, 1929 (Box 30, Folder 55)
  - Rev. Andrew Richards, 1926 1969; 1926-1969; 21 Items
    This sub-series contains records related to Andrew Richards's time as pastor. Included are baptisms, work files, installation, marriages, funerals, members received, anniversary invitations, correspondences, letters, his retirement and reports for the ecclesiastical council.
    - Reverend Andrew Richards Baptisms, 1926 1969; 1926-1969 (Box 30, Folder 20)
    - Return to Fall Schedule Notice, September 10, 1931 (Box 30, Folder 21)
    - Reverend Andrew Richards' Move to Boston, 1931 1932; 1931-1932 (Box 30, Folder 22)
    - Related to Reverend Andrew Richards' Installation, 1931 1932; 1931-1932 (Box 30, Folder 23)
    - Reverend Andrew Richards' Work Files, 1931 1932; 1931-1932 (Box 30, Folder 24)
    - Reverend Andrew Richards' Work Files, 1931 1961; 1931-1961 (Box 30, Folder 25)
    - Invitation's to Reverend Andrew Richards Installation, 1932-05 1932-06; May - June 1932 (Box 30, Folder 26)
    - Reverend Andrew Richards at the Ecclesiastical Council, May 24, 1932 (Box 30, Folder 27)
    - Reverend Andrew Richards' Marriages, 1932 1969; 1932-1969 (Box 30, Folder 28)
    - Reverend Andrew Richards' Funerals, 1932 1969; 1932-1969 (Box 30, Folder 29)
    - Reverend Andrew Richards' Members Received, 1932 1969; 1932-1969 (Box 30, Folder 30)
    - Reverend Andrew Richards' Work FIles, 1936 1967; 1936-1967 (Box 30, Folder 31)
    - Reverend Andrew Richards' Anniversary Invitations, 1942 1957; 1942-1957 (Box 30, Folder 32)
    - Reverend Andrew Richards' 15th Anniversary, February 2, 1947 (Box 30, Folder 33)
    - Reverend Andrew Richards' Correspondences and Notes, 1948 1967; 1948-1967 (Box 30, Folder 34)
    - Reverend Andrew Richards' Work FIles, 1955 1966; 1955-1966 (Box 30, Folder 35)
    - 25th Anniversary of Reverend Andrew Richards, February 1957 (Box 30, Folder 36)
    - Reverend Andrew Richards Christmas Letter, December 13, 1965 (Box 30, Folder 37)
    - Review of Reverend Andrew Richards, 1965 1967; 1965-1967 (Box 30, Folder 38)
    - Retirement of Reverend Andrew Rirchards, May 13, 1966 (Box 30, Folder 39)
    - A Triumphant Death: Meditation on 23rd Psalm, undated (Box 30, Folder 40)
  - Rev. Frank T. Jensen, 1967 1968; 1967-1968; 2 Items
    This sub-series contains the pastoral search for Frank Thomas Jensen and some of his records.
    - Pastoral Search of Frank Thomas Jensen, 1967 (Box 30, Folder 59)
    - Reverend Frank Thomas Jensen records, 1968 (Box 30, Folder 60)
  - Rev. Thomas G. Jones, 1978 1981; 1978-1981; 3 Items
    This sub-series contains the pastoral search for Thomas G. Jones, as well as his service of recognition and UCC yearbook reports.
    - Pastoral Search, 1978 1979; 1978-1979 (Box 30, Folder 69)
    - Service of Recognition for Reverend Thomas G. Jones, December 9, 1979 (Box 30, Folder 61)
    - UCC Yearbook Reports, 1980 1981; 1980-1981 (Box 30, Folder 71)
- Incorporated churches, 1888 1991; 1888-1991; 31 Items
  This series includes records related to churches that were incorporated by Second Church, including Harvard Congregational Church and Central Congregational Church.
  - Harvard Congregational Church, 1888 1991; 1888-1940, 1988-1991; 18 Items